collecting postage stamps is a worldwide
business and hobby which begun not long
after National postal Authority started
to issue stamps
the very first definitive stamp with a
hologram was issued in Austria in 1988.
since then in 2005 about 50 countries
have issued holographic stamps and the
total amount of different postal items
with Holograms is well over 100. in 1999
and 2000 there were more holographic
stamps issued than in any previous years
the use of holograms on stamps seems to
be more of a new and attractive
decoration rather than a security
measure holographic stamps have already
become a new philatelic topical field
probably the first time philatelists
were exposed to holography was in 1974
in Sweden at the international stamp
exhibition stockholmia 74 a hologram of
the coronation crown of Eric the 14th
from 1561 was on display at the show
on October 20th 1971 the Swedish post
issued a series of five stamps featuring
The Royal Treasures including the crown
since it was not possible to show the
real crown at the stamp exhibition a
hologram of the crown was produced
the recording of the 8x10 off-axis
transmission hologram was performed in
the cellar under the royal castle and
Stockholm during the night of August
20th 1974 the crown was moved from the
treasury down to a room in the cellar
the Hologram was installed in a special
display case in which the Hologram was
illuminated with yellow filtered light
from a Mercury Arc lamp placed at the
bottom of the display case
the Hologram was a main attraction at
the show and people were waiting in a
long line to be able to get a glimpse of
the holographic Crown as a matter of
fact many people came to the stamp show
just to see the hologram
in 1986 there was a Statue of Liberty
hologram attached to the exhibition
catalog for the U.S stamp exhibition
ameriplex 86 in Chicago which took place
between May 22nd and June 1st a smaller
version of the same hologram was used
for a French American postcard jointly
issued on July 4th 1986 for the 100 year
anniversary of the Statue of Liberty
in connection with the 1986 German
holographic exhibition in Karl shrew
between October 11th and December 7th
Deutsche buns post issued a special
machine cancellation the cancellation
contained Hollow media fascination with
light and sound
at an Australian stamp exhibition Expo
88 a souvenir cover had a hologram
version of the Expo 88 stamp attached to
the envelope which was issued on April
30th 1988 the opening day of the
exhibition the stamp World Expo was held
in Brisbane and the theme of the Expo
was leisure in the age of Technology
on November 30th 1988 Hungary issued a
stamp without a hologram Dennis Gabor
the inventor of holography
stamp is from a series of Hungarian
Nobel Prize winners Gabor received the
1971 physics Nobel Prize for his
invention of holography which he had
done already in 1948. not until the
early 1960s when the laser had been
invented was it possible to demonstrate
the potential of gabor's remarkable 3D
imaging technique
in People's Republic of China every year
normally on January 5th since 1987 China
National philatelic Corporation has
issued a new year presentation folder
with an embossed hologram of the animal
of the year the first such folder was
the 1987 one with a hologram of a rabbit
the Hologram was attached to the cover
page of the folder there are four
ordinary Chinese stamps attached to the
left inside page of the folder
second and subsequent folders have the
Hologram attached inside the folder
as already mentioned in the introduction
holography was theoretically invented by
Dennis gabora 1948 but not convincingly
demonstrated until the early 1960s
since then there have been various
holographic techniques developed
applications of holography are found in
3D display techniques scientific
high-resolution Imaging applications for
recording diffractive Optical elements
and many more one important application
is the use of holograms as an optical
variable device on documents as a
security measure most well known here is
the use of embossed mass-produced
Holograms and credit cards the types of
holograms are the ones which have been
used on postage stamps
the holographic technique used for such
Holograms is known as rainbow hologram
or Benton Holograms named after the
inventor and MIT Professor St em Benton
the advantage of this technique is that
it is possible to see the image without
Illuminating the whole gram with a laser
as well as that is possible to make them
in large quantities using simple
embossing techniques
on October 18
1988 Austria issued the first definitive
postage stamp with an embossed hologram
the Hologram features a 3D image of a
shipping crate which floats behind a 2d
graphic which combines a capital A and
made in Austria to highlight Austrian
export
the stamp was issued at the 1988 export
Convention of the Chamber of Commerce
it is an eight-shilling stamp issued in
Pains of eight stamps
3.04 million stamps were issued
stamp was designed by Wolfgang stalker
the design of the Hologram for the stamp
was made by 3D AG in Switzerland
in cooperation with Gunther Dawson at
holotronics
Germany where the master was recorded
Leonard Kurtz in Germany produced the
embossed Holograms
Austrian banknote printing company
attached the Holograms to the stamps as
well as printed the stamps the issue
sold out in three days